<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cycling Safety on It's All Downhill From Here</title><link>/categories/cycling-safety/</link><description>Recent content in Cycling Safety on It's All Downhill From Here</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cycling-safety/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tires - Be Faster, Safer, More Comfortable</title><link>/pages/cyclingsafety/tire_safety/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/cyclingsafety/tire_safety/</guid><description>In cycling, “contact points” are critical: bum on saddle, hands on handlebars, feet on pedals. But the most important one of all is “where the rubber meets the road”. Tires may be the most important component on your bike. The right tire at the right pressure makes a huge difference to your safety - your “grip” on the road - as well as to your comfort, and efficiency.
Diving into detail on tires, with a focus on tire width, tire pressure, and tire quality, we will discover:</description></item><item><title>How to Crash</title><link>/pages/cyclingsafety/how_to_crash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/cyclingsafety/how_to_crash/</guid><description>You will crash - learn to crash properly I’m in the middle of a tight pack of two dozen racers at the Pan-Am Games velodrome, 5 laps from the end of the race, averaging 45kph. There’s a sudden slowing as riders position themselves for the finishing sprint. I hear swearing, and the unmistakable sound of carbon wheels scraping each other as multiple riders make contact at speed. A rider just above me goes down and slides across my rear wheel.</description></item><item><title>How not to Fall (at low speed)</title><link>/pages/cyclingsafety/how_not_to_fall/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/cyclingsafety/how_not_to_fall/</guid><description>In the previous article, we mentioned that many serious cycling injuries happen when cyclists are slowing and preparing to stop. So let’s discuss some techniques to prevent low speed falls.
Now all this may seem like a lot of effort. But it’s much preferable to broken bones! (As the old aged goes… you can say me now or pay me later!)
Cleats and Unclipping How many times have you heard:</description></item><item><title>Every Cyclist Crashes - Even You!</title><link>/pages/cyclingsafety/everyone_crashes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/cyclingsafety/everyone_crashes/</guid><description>I’ll be blunt: “Given the amount of time I spend on a bike, I recognize there is a significant probability that my cycling career, or even my life, could end as a result of a serious cycling accident”. As a cyclist, the risk of injury requiring hospital treatment (per km travelled) is significantly greater than when in a motor vehicle. The more you cycle, the greater the risk - You will crash!</description></item><item><title>After You Crash &amp; Your Helmet Saves Your Head!</title><link>/pages/cyclingsafety/after_you_crash/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/cyclingsafety/after_you_crash/</guid><description>BANG! Hisss…! A Puncture! But who? Where? I’m riding in a peloton of 24 tightly packed riders in the middle of the steep banking on the Pan-Am Games Velodrome in Milton Ontario. It’s impossible to stay up on the banking after a puncture. Everyone knows someone is going down, and is going to take other riders with them. I’m a loser of this lottery. The rider with the puncture slides down in front of me and I flip over their bike at 34KPH, as four of us go down.</description></item></channel></rss>