<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on It's All Downhill From Here</title><link>/categories/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on It's All Downhill From Here</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/categories/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Colophon - How this Site is Made</title><link>/about/colophon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/colophon/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;figure class="right">&lt;img src="../images/hugo-logo-200px.png"
 alt="Hugo logo" width="150">
&lt;/figure>

This site is written in &lt;a href="https://www.markdownguide.org/">Markdown&lt;/a> and generated with the static site generator (SSG) &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo&lt;/a>. Markdown is a simple plain text document format that can be easily and quickly processed to generate html, pdf, .docx, and a number of other file formats. I use it for just about all my writing - for documents and articles (I avoid Microsoft Word at all costs!), note taking, and for writing web pages. Hugo quickly generates an efficient website. Since the website is made up only of static webpages and a little JavaScript, it renders fast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started with the &lt;a href="https://github.com/Vimux/Mainroad">Mainroad&lt;/a> theme, and gradually added customizations and extensions. (I spend way too much time fretting about formatting and not nearly enough time actually writing content - And the results are pretty mediocre in any case!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Clubs and Activities</title><link>/about/clubs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/clubs/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="cycling-clubs">Cycling Clubs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since my biggest activity is cycling, I&amp;rsquo;m of course, a member of multiple clubs and organizations:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.ottawabicycleclub.ca/">&lt;img src="../images/OBC-400x229.png" alt="Ottawa Bicycle Club" width="125px" class="left">&lt;/a> The &lt;a href="https://www.ottawabicycleclub.ca/">OBC&lt;/a> is my &amp;ldquo;home club&amp;rdquo;. One of largest cycling club&amp;rsquo;s in Canada, with over 1,000 members, the OBC offers touring, gravel riding, time trials, and various events like the &lt;a href="https://www.ottawabicycleclub.ca/rlct/">Rideau Lakes Cycle Tour&lt;/a>.
&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://knbc.ca/">&lt;img src="../images/knbc.jpg" alt="Kanata Nepean Bicycle Club" width="125px" class="left">&lt;/a> The &lt;a href="https://knbc.ca/">Kanata Nepean Bicycle Club&lt;/a> is a purely recreational touring club - I do most of my touring rides with the KNBC.
&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cccts.org/">&lt;img src="../images/CCCTS.jpg" alt="Cross Canada Cycle Touring Society" width="125px" class="left">&lt;/a> The &lt;a href="https://cccts.org//">Cross Canada Cycle Touring Society&lt;/a> is another purely recreational touring club - They have chapters in British Columbia as well as Ottawa. They organize a lot of away tours, including many outside of North America. My wife and I do most of our multi-day &amp;ldquo;away&amp;rdquo; cycle touring with the CCCTS.
&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About Bill Bourne - Life Behind Bars</title><link>/about/aboutbillbourne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/aboutbillbourne/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="center">&lt;img src="../images/gravel-life-behind-bars-banner.jpeg"
 alt="Life Behind Bars" width="100%">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;hr>
&lt;figure class="left">&lt;img src="../images/bill-on-track.jpg"
 alt="Bill Playing in the Mud" width="250">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;p>While I&amp;rsquo;ve not given up my love of software technology completely, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved from coaching software developers to coaching young cyclists. I&amp;rsquo;m a &lt;a href="https://coach.ca/national-coaching-certification-program">National Coaching Certification Program (NCCP)&lt;/a> trained coach, and coach youth in the &lt;a href="https://www.ottawabicycleclub.ca/index.php/youth-program">OBC’s Youth Development Program&lt;/a>. I’m a &lt;a href="https://canbikecanada.ca/">Cycling Canada CanBike instructor&lt;/a>, and I teach riding skills, traffic safety, and ride leading to adults.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also volunteer, both in Ottawa and at the &lt;a href="https://www.milton.ca/en/arts-and-recreation/mattamy-national-cycling-centre.aspx">Mattamy National Cycling Center&lt;/a> velodrome in Milton. I help within in my bike clubs, as well as helping to run cycling events.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through the &lt;a href="https://ociso.org/career-mentorship/">OCISO Career Mentoring Program&lt;/a>, I also mentor international professionals who are new immigrants to Canada - supporting them in their quest to establish themselves in a career in Canada.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About this site</title><link>/about/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>I use this site to post notes about cycling, (especially track cycling, and cycling education), technology, and other random topics. It&amp;rsquo;s my place to put various articles and information that I feel like sharing. Sometimes feel compelled to opine on a topic. I don&amp;rsquo;t rally expect people to read my writings, but maybe the odd person will find something useful!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I was working, I had a blog where I wrote technology articles. This website is focussed on cycling articles, since that&amp;rsquo;s my current passion.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="its-all-downhill-from-here">&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s All Downhill From Here&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure class="left">&lt;img src="../images/gravel-calls.jpeg"
 alt="Gravel Calls" width="250">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;p>As an active senior citizen cyclist, I find the double entendre really appropriate.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>