<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>It's All Downhill From Here</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on It's All Downhill From Here</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 21:41:45 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The world is getting better</title><link>/hidden/better_world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 21:41:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>/hidden/better_world/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m reading Peter Singer&amp;rsquo;s book The Life You can Save (you can freely download the book from the website), in which he makes a profound observation. He challenges the assumption about our behavior that permeates western, and particularly American, culture: &amp;ldquo;the norm of self-interest&amp;rdquo;:
Alexis de Tocqueville, that sharp observer of the American psyche during the formative years of the United States, noticed the norm even then: “Americans,” he wrote in 1835, “enjoy explaining almost every act of their lives on the principle of self-interest.</description></item><item><title>Timeless Rules of Software Development</title><link>/hidden/timeless-software-dev/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hidden/timeless-software-dev/</guid><description>Rules Fail Fast Be Paranoid Avoid inserting defects Find/Fix Defects Close to where they are inserted Accept and deal with the 4Fs of war - friction, fog, fluidity, fatigue</description></item><item><title>Tires - Be Faster, Safer, More Comfortable</title><link>/cyclingsafety/tire-safety/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cyclingsafety/tire-safety/</guid><description>In cycling, “contact points” are critical: bum on saddle, hands on handlebars, feet on pedals. But the most important one of all is “where the rubber meets the road”. Tires may be the most important component on your bike. The right tire at the right pressure makes a huge difference to your safety - your “grip” on the road - as well as to your comfort, and efficiency.
Diving into detail on tires, with a focus on tire width, tire pressure, and tire quality, we will discover:</description></item><item><title>How to Crash</title><link>/cyclingsafety/how_to_crash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cyclingsafety/how_to_crash/</guid><description>You will crash - learn to crash properly I’m in the middle of a tight pack of two dozen racers at the Pan-Am Games velodrome, 5 laps from the end of the race, averaging 45kph. There’s a sudden slowing as riders position themselves for the finishing sprint. I hear swearing, and the unmistakable sound of carbon wheels scraping each other as multiple riders make contact at speed. A rider just above me goes down and slides across my rear wheel.</description></item><item><title>How not to Fall (at low speed)</title><link>/cyclingsafety/how_not_to_fall/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cyclingsafety/how_not_to_fall/</guid><description>In the previous article, we mentioned that many serious cycling injuries happen when cyclists are slowing and preparing to stop. So let’s discuss some techniques to prevent low speed falls.
Now all this may seem like a lot of effort. But it’s much preferable to broken bones! (As the old aged goes… you can say me now or pay me later!)
Cleats and Unclipping How many times have you heard:</description></item><item><title>Every Cyclist Crashes - Even You!</title><link>/cyclingsafety/everyone_crashes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cyclingsafety/everyone_crashes/</guid><description>I’ll be blunt: “Given the amount of time I spend on a bike, I recognize there is a significant probability that my cycling career, or even my life, could end as a result of a serious cycling accident”. As a cyclist, the risk of injury requiring hospital treatment (per km travelled) is significantly greater than when in a motor vehicle. The more you cycle, the greater the risk - You will crash!</description></item><item><title>After You Crash &amp; Your Helmet Saves Your Head!</title><link>/cyclingsafety/after_you_crash/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cyclingsafety/after_you_crash/</guid><description>BANG! Hisss…! A Puncture! But who? Where? I’m riding in a peloton of 24 tightly packed riders in the middle of the steep banking on the Pan-Am Games Velodrome in Milton Ontario. It’s impossible to stay up on the banking after a puncture. Everyone knows someone is going down, and is going to take other riders with them. I’m a loser of this lottery. The rider with the puncture slides down in front of me and I flip over their bike at 34KPH, as four of us go down.</description></item><item><title>The Joy of Recreational Track Cycling</title><link>/tracknut/joy_of_track/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/tracknut/joy_of_track/</guid><description>In the depths of winter, options for cycling become less appealing… Do I ride outdoors in the cold, wet, and wind? Or sweat it out indoors on a trainer, listening to music or a video to combat the boredom?
There’s another option! With the construction of the Mattamy National Cycling Centre for the Pan Am Games, there’s a beautiful world-class indoor velodrome facility within reasonable driving distance of Ottawa. I expect many people associate “velodrome” with competitive cycling - that it’s just for the racers, cyclo-sportifs, the “really fast guys”.</description></item><item><title>Velodrome Basics</title><link>/tracknut/about_velodromes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/tracknut/about_velodromes/</guid><description>&lt;p>This page gives you a detailed tour around velodromes, using the two indoor velodromes in Ontario as examples:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ontario Track Cycling Resources</title><link>/tracknut/ontario_track_resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/tracknut/ontario_track_resources/</guid><description>&lt;p>This page contains links to velodromes and organizations of interest to riders in Ontario&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Essential Rules of the Track</title><link>/tracknut/basic_rules/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/tracknut/basic_rules/</guid><description>&lt;p>This page is deliberately short. We ride the track &lt;em>a lot&lt;/em> and we keep coming across people not following these essential rules, resulting is quite a number of close calls. Crashes in recreational track cycling are rare, and we want to keep them that way!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Markdown Formatting</title><link>/playground/markdown-formatting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/playground/markdown-formatting/</guid><description>Introduction Many Flavours of Markdown There are many variants of Markdown formats, and each processor may support a range of extensions, and interpret the Markdown specifications in somwhat different ways. The main formats include:
Markdown - this is the classic orginal version Multimarkdown - the orginal extension to Markdown GitHub Flavored Markdown -a small set of extension to Markdown defined by GitHub Kramdown - extensive set of extensions based on PHP markdown Extra package and Maruku Pandoc - extensive set of extensions, but strays from the original markdown syntax and extensions somewhat Markdown Processors There are also many different Markdown processors, each with their own quirks.</description></item><item><title>About Bill Bourne</title><link>/about/aboutbillbourne/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/aboutbillbourne/</guid><description>I started programming in 1972 (Fortran, APL, assembler) Even though my university degree was in Electrical Engineering, my whole professional career has been software related. I became a manager in 1981, although I continued to write production code until 1986. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to keep my hand in, even as I became a senior manager and a director.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been a principal founder of a video games start-up, had 2 games on the Billboard top 40, and wrote applications for Apple and Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>Hugo's Markdown Extensions</title><link>/playground/testpage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/playground/testpage/</guid><description>Introduction This article focuses on markdown as supported by Hugo and Pandoc. Here are a few good Markdown references and tutorials:
Markdown Guide Wikipedia Markdown entry CommonMark - the markdown &amp;ldquo;standard&amp;rdquo; Hugo&amp;rsquo;s Markdown Hugo uses the GoldMark as it&amp;rsquo;s default Markdown processor. Goldmark supports the CommonMark standard, along with:
Tables, Strikethrough, Autolinks, TaskLists from GitHub-Flavored Markdown Definition Lists and Footnotes from PHP Markdown Extra Special typographic characters from SmartyPants Embedded HTML may be enabled in the Hugo Site Configuration Attribute lists on headings and block elements to add styling.</description></item><item><title>Template Page</title><link>/playground/template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/playground/template/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Using ASCIIMath and MathJax</title><link>/playground/mathtest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/playground/mathtest/</guid><description>This page tests and documents using MathJax, Latex and AsciiMath with Hugo and markdown.
Getting a Markdown Processor to Ignore Markup MathJax, AsciiMath, and similar processors use special markup characters in the the html file. Often these characters overlap with markdown&amp;rsquo;s markup, and the markdown processor will mess things up. There are a number of options:
Use the \ backslash, which is markdown&amp;rsquo;s escape character, to escape characters that would be processed by markdown.</description></item></channel></rss>