<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Categories on It's All Downhill From Here</title><link>/categories/</link><description>Recent content in Categories on It's All Downhill From Here</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cycling Education</title><link>/categories/cycling-safety/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/categories/cycling-safety/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;figure class="right">&lt;img src="/categories/cycling-safety/Bill_Coaching1_Bromont-small.jpg"
 alt="Bill Coaching at the Velodrome" width="90%">
&lt;/figure>

Post retirement I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself drawn into cycling coaching. I coach youth in the &lt;a href="https://www.ottawabicycleclub.ca/index.php/youth-program">OBC&amp;rsquo;s Youth Development Program&lt;/a>, and I&amp;rsquo;m a &lt;a href="http://canbikecanada.ca/">Cycling Canada CanBike&lt;/a> instructor. I also teach riding skills, traffic safety, and ride leading to adults.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The best way to learn something well is to teach it to someone else. It forces you to reflect deeply on what you think you know. This is especially true of coaching. By approaching coaching with humility and a passion for the subject, I find I&amp;rsquo;m always learning and growing.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>“Given the amount of time I spend on a bike, I recognize there is a significant probability that my cycling career, or even my life, could end as a result of a serious cycling accident”. As a cyclist, the risk of injury requiring hospital treatment (per km traveled) is significantly greater than when in a motor vehicle. The more you cycle, the greater the risk.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Technology</title><link>/categories/technology/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/categories/technology/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can find all my technology notes archived below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="articles-in-this-series">Articles in This Series:&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Track Cycling</title><link>/categories/track-cycling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/categories/track-cycling/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="center">&lt;img src="/categories/track-cycling/img/track-cover-photo-2.jpg">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note:&lt;/strong> This series of articles was written in 2017 on their own website, then abandoned. I&amp;rsquo;ve resurrected and updated them here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back in 2015, I re-discovered the joy of track cycling after 30 years absence from the track. With the construction of the &lt;a href="http://www.mattamynationalcyclingcentre.ca/en/index.asp">Mattamy National Cycling Centre&lt;/a> in Milton for the Pan-Am games, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the lure of an international class velodrome within driving distance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also volunteer, at the track helping to run events. And I coach, supporting &lt;a href="https://www.ottawabicycleclub.ca/">Ottawa Bicycle Club&lt;/a> Youth and Racing program athletes at the &lt;a href="http://www.mattamynationalcyclingcentre.ca/en/index.asp">Mattamy National Cycling Centre&lt;/a>, or at one of our two other velodromes in the region - &lt;a href="https://centrenationalbromont.com/velodrome-multisports/">Centre National de Cyclisme de Bromont&lt;/a> south of Montreal and the &lt;a href="https://www.forestcityvelodrome.ca/">Forest City Velodrome&lt;/a> in London Ontario.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>