<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crashing on It&#39;s All Downhill From Here</title>
    <link>/tags/crashing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crashing on It&#39;s All Downhill From Here</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 14:41:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/crashing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Crash</title>
      <link>/cyclingsafety/how_to_crash/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/cyclingsafety/how_to_crash/</guid>
      <description>In this article we’ll discuss how to minimize injury if to &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; crash. Of course there are no guarantees, but there are techniques you can use to minimize injuries when you crash. There are 3 aspects to minimizing the seriousness of your injuries - Fitness, Technique and Training.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How not to Fall (at low speed)</title>
      <link>/cyclingsafety/how_not_to_fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/cyclingsafety/how_not_to_fall/</guid>
      <description>Many serious cycling injuries happen when cyclists are slowing and preparing to stop. There are techniques we can use to prevent low speed falls. While this may seem like a lot of effort, it’s much preferable to broken bones!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Every Cyclist Crashes - Even You!</title>
      <link>/cyclingsafety/everyone_crashes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/cyclingsafety/everyone_crashes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;Given the amount of time I spend on a bike, I recognize there is a significant probability that my cycling career, or even my life, could end as a result of a serious cycling accident&lt;/strong&gt;”.&#xA;As a cyclist, the risk of injury requiring hospital treatment  (per km travelled) is significantly greater than when in a motor vehicle. The more you cycle, the greater the risk - &lt;strong&gt;You will crash!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After You Crash &amp; Your Helmet Saves Your Head!</title>
      <link>/cyclingsafety/after_you_crash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/cyclingsafety/after_you_crash/</guid>
      <description>After a crash, the adrenaline will be pumping… an injured rider will not necessarily feel pain, and often will say “I’m OK” and want to get back on their bike. NO! Take it slow and do a thorough check - there&amp;rsquo;s a post-crash list to follow.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
