<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Equipment on It's All Downhill From Here</title><link>/tags/equipment/</link><description>Recent content in Equipment on It's All Downhill From Here</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 15:03:58 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/equipment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Running Tubeless? Things you Need to Know!</title><link>/cyclingsafety/tubeless_caveats/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cyclingsafety/tubeless_caveats/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many recreational cyclists are using tubeless tires without understanding how to maintain them, or their downsides.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Sealant must be replaced every few months, at least once a season.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sealant does not always seal a hole, especially if the hole is larger than a few mm.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You need to carry either a spare tube (and a tool to remove the tubeless value) or tire plugs and a small tube of sealant&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Having sealant spewing out can get really messy!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can&amp;rsquo;t go about 75psi with tubeless tires, so tubeless and skinny tires don&amp;rsquo;t work together. Jay Heins of Hene Herse, who makes some of the world&amp;rsquo;s best tubeless tires says don&amp;rsquo;t go about 6-psi.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Valve core clogs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tubeless tires are much more diufficult to install and remove. It can be difficult to get the bead to seal on the rim - often rapid inflation with a special &amp;ldquo;charger pump&amp;rdquo; or an air compressor is required.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.renehersecycles.com/the-trouble-with-road-tubeless/">The trouble with road tubeless&lt;/a> - Rene Herse
&lt;a href="https://road.cc/content/feature/9-things-they-dont-tell-you-about-tubeless-tyres-257746">Nine things they don&amp;rsquo;t tell you about tuneless tires&lt;/a> - road.cc&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tires - Be Faster, Safer, More Comfortable</title><link>/cyclingsafety/tire-safety/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cyclingsafety/tire-safety/</guid><description>The most important contact point on a bike is “where the rubber meets the road”. Tires may be the most important component on your bike. The right tire at the right pressure makes a huge difference to your safety - your “grip” on the road - as well as to your comfort, and efficiency. You can have it all with wider tires.</description></item></channel></rss>