<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Track Nut - The Fun of Ontario Track Cycling on It's All Downhill From Here</title><link>/hidden/tracknut/</link><description>Recent content in Track Nut - The Fun of Ontario Track Cycling on It's All Downhill From Here</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/hidden/tracknut/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sizes of Our Local Velodromes</title><link>/hidden/tracknut/velodrome_sizes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hidden/tracknut/velodrome_sizes/</guid><description>Sizes of our local velodromes Velodrome Length Bank Angle Track Width Straight Angle Length at Rail Radius Milton 250 42 7 12 285 UCI Cat 1 250 42-45 ?? 7-8 12-13 285 ?? 19-25 FCV 138 51 4.8 17 ?? https://plus.maths.org/content/leaning-2012 - great article of physics of velodrome bankings
http://www.physicsclassroom.com/class/circles/u6l2c.cfm
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Banked_turn
https://vimeo.com/27977724 - series of vimeo videos on physics of pursuiting.
http://www.kenhart.com/ - strategies for track cycling races, etc</description></item><item><title>The Joy of Recreational Track Cycling</title><link>/hidden/tracknut/joy_of_track/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hidden/tracknut/joy_of_track/</guid><description>In the depths of winter, options for cycling become less appealing… Do I ride outdoors in the cold, wet, and wind? Or sweat it out indoors on a trainer, listening to music or a video to combat the boredom?
There’s another option! With the construction of the Mattamy National Cycling Centre for the Pan Am Games, there’s a beautiful world-class indoor velodrome facility within reasonable driving distance of Ottawa. I expect many people associate “velodrome” with competitive cycling - that it’s just for the racers, cyclo-sportifs, the “really fast guys”.</description></item><item><title>Velodrome Basics</title><link>/hidden/tracknut/about_velodromes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hidden/tracknut/about_velodromes/</guid><description>&lt;p>This page gives you a detailed tour around velodromes, using the two indoor velodromes in Ontario as examples:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ontario Track Cycling Resources</title><link>/hidden/tracknut/ontario_track_resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hidden/tracknut/ontario_track_resources/</guid><description>&lt;p>This page contains links to velodromes and organizations of interest to riders in Ontario&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Essential Rules of the Track</title><link>/hidden/tracknut/basic_rules/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hidden/tracknut/basic_rules/</guid><description>&lt;p>This page is deliberately short. We ride the track &lt;em>a lot&lt;/em> and we keep coming across people not following these essential rules, resulting is quite a number of close calls. Crashes in recreational track cycling are rare, and we want to keep them that way!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>