<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About this site on It's All Downhill From Here</title><link>/about/</link><description>Recent content in About this site on It's All Downhill From Here</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Colophon - How this Site is Made</title><link>/about/colophon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/colophon/</guid><description>How? (About the Technology) This site is generated with the static site generator (SSG) Hugo. This allows me to:
Write my content using Markdown. Markdown is a simple plain text document format that can be easily and quickly processed to generate html, pdf, .docx, and a number of other file formats.</description></item><item><title>My Clubs and Activities</title><link>/about/clubs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/clubs/</guid><description>Cycling Since my biggest activity is cycling, I&amp;rsquo;m of course, a member of multiple clubs and organizations:
Ottawa Bicycle Club is my &amp;ldquo;home club&amp;rdquo;. One of largest cycling club&amp;rsquo;s in Canada, with over 1,000 members, the OBC offers touring, gravel riding, time trials, and various events like the Rideal Lakes Cycle Tour.</description></item><item><title>About Bill Bourne</title><link>/about/aboutbillbourne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/aboutbillbourne/</guid><description>Life Behind Bars While I&amp;rsquo;ve not given up my love of software technology and development practices completely, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved from coaching software developers to coaching young cyclists. I&amp;rsquo;m a National Coaching Certification Program (NCCP) trained coach and coach youth in the OBC’s Youth Development Program. I’m a Cycling Canada CanBike instructor, and I teach riding skills, traffic safety, and ride leading to adults.</description></item><item><title>About this site</title><link>/about/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/about/</guid><description>Why? This site is my place to put various articles and information that I feel like sharing. Sometimes feel compelled to opine on a topic. I don&amp;rsquo;t rally expect people to read my writings, but maybe the odd person will find something useful!
What? When I was working, I had a blog where I wrote technology articles.</description></item></channel></rss>